Guide to the Office of Government Relations Records, 1965-1983
Duke University. University Archives
Office of Government Relations records 1965-1983
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Office of Government Relations
13.125 linear feet Extent: 10,500 Items
This collection contains the records of the Office of Government Relations from the tenure of Eugene J. Macdonald. The Office of Government Relations is charged with representing the University in Washington, D.C., and in state government. In 1999 the office became the point of contact on health-related issues at the federal level for Duke University Health System (DUHS) and state government issues for Duke University and DUHS. The materials span the years of 1965 to 1983. Major topics include legislation, lobbying, NAICU, and the AAU.
UA.12.01.0001
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Office of Government Relations Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1985.
Historical Note
The Office of Government Relations is charged with representing the University in Washington, D.C., and in state government. In 1999 the office became the point of contact on health-related issues at the federal level for Duke University Health System (DUHS) and state government issues for Duke University and DUHS.
Collection Overview
The collection contains memoranda, correspondence, and other papers from E.J. McDonald's tenure in the Office of Government Relations. Subjects include lobbying in NC; RUN (Research University Network); Association of American Universities (AAU), NC Legislation, American Council on Education (ACE); Regan Economic Recovery; Research Legislation; National Association of Independent Colleges and Universities (NAICU); and Reauthorization of Higher Education Act. The materials range in date from 1965-1983.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series: AAU, Committees and Councils, Federal Relations, General Files, Legislation, Lobbying, NAICU, and Reports and Memos. The series are arranged alphabetically as are the files within each series.
Subject Headings
Duke University. Office of Government Relations; Association of American Universities; American Council on Education; National Association of Independent Colleges and Universities; McDonald, E.J.
Related Material
H. Keith H. Brodie, President, Records, 1963-1994
Duke University Archives
H. Keith H. Brodie, Chancellor, Records, 1970-1985
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- AAU, (1.5 boxes)
  Conatains files related to the Association of American Universities.
  - A-21 Meeting, 1982 (1 of 3) (Box 1)
  - A-21 Meeting, 1982 (2 of 3) (Box 1)
  - A-21 Meeting, 1982 (3 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Briefing File, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Briefing Papers, 1983 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Briefing Papers, 1980-1982 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - General Files, 1977 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - General Files, 1977 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Office of Management and Budget, 1980-1984 (1 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Office of Management and Budget, 1980-1984 (2 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Office of Management and Budget, 1980-1984 (3 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Office of Management and Budget, 1978-1979 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Office of Management and Budget, 1978-1979 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Reports and Memos 1979-1980 (1 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Reports and Memos 1979-1980 (2 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Reports and Memos 1979-1980 (3 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Research Universities Network 1980-1983 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Research Universities Network 1980-1983 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Reports, Memos and Papers, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Reports, Memos and Papers, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Reports, Memos and Papers, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Reports, Memos and Papers, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Reports, Memos and Papers, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Reports, Memos and Papers, 1978 (1 of 3) (Box 2)
  - Reports, Memos and Papers, 1978 (2 of 3) (Box 2)
  - Reports, Memos and Papers, 1978 (3 of 3) (Box 2)
- Committees and Councils, (1 box)
  - Ad Hoc Taxation of Fringe Benefits - Tuition Remission, 1978-1981 (Box 2)
  - Ad Hoc: Tax Reform Issues - 2, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Ad Hoc: Tax Reform Issues - 2, 1974-1979 (Box 2)
  - Ad Hoc: Tax Meeting, Washington, D.C., 1983 (Box 2)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Science Policy, 1978-1980 (Box 2)
  - Advisory Committee on Education, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Law Reform, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education File 1, 1979 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education File 1, 1977-1979 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education File 2, 1982 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education File 2, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Consortium on Financing Higher Education, 1982-1984 (Box 3)
  - Consortium on Financing Higher Education, 1978-1980 (Box 3)
  - Consortium on Financing Higher Education, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Council on Wage and Price Stability, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Council on Wage and Price Stability, 1979 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Council on Wage and Price Stability, 1979 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Council on Wage and Price Stability File 2, 1980 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Council on Wage and Price Stability File 2, 1980 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Council on Wage and Price Stability File 2, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Committee on More Effective Government HR. 6380 (Bolling), 1980 (Box 3)
  - Friends of Health - General, 1979-1981 (Box 3)
  - Friends of Health: 1979 and Older (Box 3)
  - Friends of Health Meeting: Washington, D.C. April 18, 1979 (Box 3)
  - National Commission on Research Reports, 1980 (Box 3)
  - National Security - Classification, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Ways and Means Committee of the House, 1974-1978 (Box 3)
- Federal Relations, (1 box)
  - Budget, 1979 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Budget, 1979 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Mining Fellowships, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Lobbying Legislation, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Committee on Federal Relations for the University, 1978 (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Committee on Federal Relations for the University, 1978 (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Council on Federal Relation, 1976-1981 (Box 4)
  - Cost Containment Bill (Philanthropy), 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Debt Financing Provision S. 2498, May 1982 (Box 4)
  - Federal Relations Committee, 1978-1981 (Box 4)
  - Legislative 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Meeting, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Meeting, April 30, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Meeting, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Misc. Research Items: Schools and Government Involvement, 1976-1978 (Box 4)
  - Position Papers, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Position Papers, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Tuition Tax Credit File 1, 1978 (1 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Tuition Tax Credit File 1, 1978 (2 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Tuition Tax Credit File 2, 1978 (1 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Tuition Tax Credit File 2, 1978 (2 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Tuition Tax Credit File 3, 1978 (1 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Tuition Tax Credit File 3, 1978 (2 of 2) (Box 4)
- General Files, (1 box)
  - Article Re: Corporations, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Congressional Replies, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Exchange of Scientific Information, 1981 (Box 4)
  - General Assembly, 1983 (1 of 3) (Box 4)
  - General Assembly, 1983 (2 of 3) (Box 4)
  - General Assembly, 1983 (3 of 3) (Box 4)
  - Legislative Relations: Testimony on Committee Finance, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Memos Between Lucy and E.J. McDonald, 1978-1981 (Box 5)
  - National Governers' Association Position Paper on Education, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Proposed Department Regulations, 1979-1981 (Box 5)
  - Research, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Retirement, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Service Contract of 1965, 1980-1982 (Box 5)
  - Social Security, 1978-1981 (1 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Social Security, 1978-1981 (2 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Spring Meeting April 12-14, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Uniform Procurement Regulations File 1, 1980 (1 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Uniform Procurement Regulations File 1, 1980 (2 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Uniform Procurement Regulations File 2, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Uniform Procurement Regulations File 2, 1976 (Box 5)
- Legislation, (1.5 boxes)
  - Academic Freedom Act S. 519, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Ad Hoc Tax Group: Misc. Memos and Papers, 1978-1982 (Box 5)
  - Charitable Contribution and Tax, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Charitable Contribution and Tax, 1973-1979 (Box 5)
  - Charitable Contribution and Tax, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Charitable Giving, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Charitable Giving, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
  - Dole/Bayh Bill: University and Small Business Patent Policy, 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Education Department and Misc. Education Legislation, 1980-1982 (Box 5)
  - Education Department and Misc. Education Legislation, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Education Department and Misc. Education Legislation, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Educational Savings Accounts, 1980-1982 (Box 6)
  - Educational Savings Accounts (Dole S. 2745), undated (Box 6)
  - Energy Legislation, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Equipment Donations Tax Act, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Ethics in Government Act, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Federal Trade Commission Jurisdiction Non-Profits, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Labor Law, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
  - N.C. Legislation - Misc. Items, 1979-1983 (Box 6)
  - North Carolina Association of Independent Colleges and Universities, 1978-1981 (Box 6)
  - North Carolina Animal Research Bill, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - N.C. State Bond Financing - Constitutional Amendment, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - N.C. Tax Exempt, 1980-1981 (Box 6)
  - N.C. Tax Exempt, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Paper Reduction Act, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Reauthorization of Higher Education Act, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Recombinant DNA Research Legislation, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Research Revitalization Act, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Regan Task Force Recommendations, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Regan Tax - Budget Cuts, 1980-1981 (1 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Regan Tax - Budget Cuts, 1980-1981 (2 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Regan Economic Recovery Tax Act, 1981 (1 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Regan Economic Recovery Tax Act, 1981 (2 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Regan Economic Recovery/1982 Budget Revisions (Box 6)
  - Regulatory Reform: Proposed Changes, Cost Savings to Universities, etc., April 1981 (1 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Regulatory Reform: Proposed Changes, Cost Savings to Universities, etc., April 1981 (2 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Research Legislation, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Solicitation Legislation: Discussion (Lucy), 1978-1980 (Box 6)
  - Sunset Bill File 1, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Sunset Bill File 1, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Sunset Bill File 2, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Sunset Bill File 2, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Tax and Higher Education, 1978 (1 of 2) (Box 7)
  - Tax and Higher Education, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Tax and Higher Education, 1978 (2 of 2) (Box 7)
  - Tax Indexation, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Tax Reform: 96th Congress, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Title VI Proposed Legislations, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Tuition Remission Materials, 1979-1981 (Box 7)
  - Tuition Tax Credit - General, 1981 (1 of 2) (Box 7)
  - Tuition Tax Credit - General, 1981 (2 of 2) (Box 7)
  - Tuition Tax Credit - Hearings, Packwood Moynihan Bill, June 3-4, 1981 (Box 7)
  - Value Added Tax Legislation, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Wage/Price Guidelines (Inflation), 1978-1979 (1 of 3) (Box 7)
  - Wage/Price Guidelines (Inflation), 1978-1979 (2 of 3) (Box 7)
  - Wage/Price Guidelines (Inflation), 1978-1979 (3 of 3) (Box 7)
- Lobbying, (.25 boxes)
  - Congressional Testimony, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Educational Institutional Lobbying Efforts, 1979-1981 (Box 7)
  - Lobbying in N.C., 1979-1982 (Box 7)
  - Sanford Testimony: Dole Education Savings Account Bill, Feb. 24, 1981 (1 of 2) (Box 7)
  - Sanford Testimony: Dole Education Savings Account Bill, Feb. 24, 1981 (2 of 2) (Box 7)
  - Terry Sanford - Testimony Before Senate, 1980 (Box 7)
- NAICU, (1 box)
  Files regarding the National Association of Independent Colleges and Universities
  - Annual Meeting, Feb. 1983 (Box 7)
  - File 2, 1982-1984 (Box 7)
  - File 2, 1982 (1 of 3) (Box 7)
  - File 2, 1982 (2 of 3) (Box 7)
  - File 2, 1982 (3 of 3) (Box 7)
  - General Memos and Correspondence, 1980 (Box 8)
  - General Papers, 1981 (1 of 3) (Box 8)
  - General Papers, 1981 (2 of 3) (Box 8)
  - General Papers, 1981 (3 of 3) (Box 8)
  - General Papers, 1980-1981 (Box 8)
  - General Papers, 1981-1983 (Box 8)
  - Government Relations Advisory Council, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Memos, 1982-1983 (Box 8)
  - Memos, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Reports and Memos, 1978-1980 (Box 8)
  - Reports and Memos, 1977-1980 (Box 8)
  - Reports and Memos, 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Tax Policy Subcommittee Meeting, June 9, 1981 (Box 8)
  - Tax Policy Subcommittee Meeting, Sept. 8, 1982 (Box 8)
- Reports and Memos, (1 box)
  - Ad Hoc Group: Estate and Gift Taxation, 1975-1976 (1 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Ad Hoc Group: Estate and Gift Taxation, 1975-1976 (2 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Animal Hospital Report, 1978-1981 (1 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Animal Hospital Report, 1978-1981 (2 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Cost Containment - Hospital, 1978-1979 (1 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Cost Containment - Hospital, 1978-1979 (2 of 2) (Box 9)
  - Deferred Compensation, 1979-1980 (1 of 2) (Box 9)
  - Deferred Compensation, 1979-1980 (2 of 2) (Box 9)
  - Discrimination, 1982 (Box 9)
  - Draft Registration Certification, 1982 (Box 9)
  - Government Grant Contracts, 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - Government Grant Contracts, 1977-1978 (Box 9)
  - Misc. Reports and Articles, 1977-1979 (Box 9)
  - Report: "A Private University Looks at Government Regulation," 1976 (Box 9)
  - State Controlled Federal Grants - Student Loans - All Fed. Funding Education, 1981 (Box 9)